Henrique Noronha

Phone: +353 83 893 3316

E-mail: henrique.noronha@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: henriquenoronha1

Location: Blanchardstown, Dublin 15

Profile

29 years old, Irish and Brazilian national, Bachelor's in Finance & Economics, and Diploma in Big Data for Business. Main experiences in Corporate Finance, financial due diligence, finance analytics, and auditing (external and internal).

Quick and continuous learner with a very positive mind and approach. Proven track record of strong analytical and problem-solving abilities. Strong team worker with proven record of excellent communication and a friendly approach to co-workers and clients, with abilities to build and maintain relationships in a business environment.

Key Skills

Financial Analysis

Financial modelling

Data Analysis

Internal/External auditing

Centro Universitário Uni-

 Business process review/improvement

 Data visualisation developer – Power BI and Tableau

Presentation/report creating

MS Office Specialist

Expert Excel user

SQL

 Experienced with SAP and other ERP systems

 Portuguese and English native speaker

 Analytical mindset / problem solver

Education

Dublin Business School, Dublin Diploma in Big Data for Busi- Jan 2019 – Dec 2019

ness

Fametro, Fortaleza - Brazil Honours Bachelor's Degree in 2012 - 2016

Finance & Economics

Career History

Financial Analyst / Finance Analytics

Life Scientific Ltd. | Dublin Jun 2019 – Oct 2020

- Participate in the annual 5-year Business Plan and budgeting processes.
- Prepare and update forecast and budget templates for the business and its subsidiaries.
- Establish assumptions, financial modelling, consolidation, analysis, and presentation preparation.
- Preparation of Group rolling forecasts and reporting against same (risks, opportunities).
- Design, develop and maintain business analysis reports Power BI dashboards and high standard Excel reports.
- Work closely with the SAP B1 database administrator to improve quality, accuracy, and availability of data
- Automate processes in the finance department using our available tools: SQL queries for SAP B1, Power BI, SharperLight and Excel.
- Responsible for the preparation of monthly business performance reviews for all functional areas of the business and related subsidiaries.
- Analyse and suggest improvements to current systems, processes, and procedures.

• Provide finance support in relation to ad hoc requests.

Internal Audit Senior Analyst

Accenture | Dublin

Jun 2018 - Feb 2019

- Responsible for executing and providing supporting documentation to facilitate internal review activities, including process reviews, segregation of duties reviews, procedures reviews, and other global controls reviews.
- Identified opportunities for continuous improvement of accounting, financial, and other processes, and evaluation of change-driven risk.
- Leveraged the use of Tableau to assist in data visualisation for planning of audit engagements.

Project Financial Accountant

Society of Saint Vincent de Paul | Dublin

Apr 2018 - Jun 2018

Assisted the Head of Finance in the financial due diligence process (sell side) regarding the sale of various Hostel locations and activities to another Non-profit organisation.

Consultant - Transaction Services

KPMG Brazil | Fortaleza | São Paulo

Feb 2016 - Feb 2018

- Conducted financial due diligence for mergers and acquisitions of companies from various sectors.
- Applied financial modelling techniques to prepare financial Databook.
- Analysed financial statements and identified non-convertible cash items in the balance sheet, as well as
 possible adjustments to net debt, working capital and EBITDA.
- Studied and analysed information memorandums, financial statements, auditor's reports and KPI reports provided by the target company to gain insights and understand business operations.
- Managed information request lists and documents received.
- Analysed trial balances to spot fluctuations, seasonality, peaks, relevant values and "other accounts" with the purpose of requesting detailed breakdowns and explanations to scout for potential issues.
- Investigated changes and variances in account balances to assess the potential risks involved.
- Assisted in the preparation of due diligence reports, outlining key recommendations, strengths, and weaknesses.
- Applied data mining to extract information to present meaningful insights to clients.

Audit Associate

BDO Brazil | Fortaleza

May 2014 - Dec 2015

- Audited financial statements, including preparation, analysis, and review in accordance with International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS).
- Analysed financial statements to identify errors and anomalies in financial data and to resolve accounting issues.
- Mapped and evaluated internal controls environments, including risk assessments.
- Tested internal controls and operational procedures.
- Performed data cleansing and processed financial information to apply audit procedures (analytical reviews, sample testing, recalculation, substantive testing).

Interests & Hobbies

- Music, Electric/acoustic guitar
- Sports soccer, Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu
- Tech Programming / Entrepreneurship

- Gaming shooters, RPGs, Sports
- Reading, mostly non-fiction

REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST